<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 on Guy Abel</title>
    <link>/publication_types/2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 on Guy Abel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 &amp;middot; Selected posts also on &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-bloggers.com/&#34;&gt;R-bloggers&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/publication_types/2/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilateral international migration flow estimates for 200 countries</title>
      <link>/publication/bilateral-international-migration-flow-estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bilateral-international-migration-flow-estimates/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;../../rmarkdown-libs/htmlwidgets/htmlwidgets.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;../../rmarkdown-libs/pymjs/pym.v1.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;../../rmarkdown-libs/widgetframe-binding/widgetframe.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;div id=&#34;update-for-wpp2019&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Update for WPP2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper came out a day before the United Nations Population Division updated their World Population Prospects (WPP). This was unfortunate as all the estimates were based on WPP2017, which made the claim of our estimates being based on the most up to date input data was true for around one day only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To rectify, I have added an updated set of estimates based on the WPP2019 to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://figshare.com/collections/Bilateral_international_migration_flow_estimates_for_200_countries/4470464&#34;&gt;Figshare collection&lt;/a&gt;. Below is a quick summary of the changes in the updated estimates to those in the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;comparison-of-estimates-based-on-wpp2017-and-wpp2019&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Comparison of estimates based on WPP2017 and WPP2019&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the plot below are scatter charts of the bilateral estimates in each period and method (based on the two most recent WPP versions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/sd-compare1.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the stock differencing methods there are no changes in the estimates. They do not rely on WPP data. The migration rates approach uses the total absolute net migration data from WPP. All bilateral flows from WPP2019 are slightly higher than their WPP2017 counterparts, though it is barely noticeable in the plots above. The demographic accounting methods use the birth, death and population estimates from the WPP. In each method there are some sizable differences for the flows generated by updated revisions to the WPP demographic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These difference results in revisions to the overall totals of migration flows. Below is an animation of the changes to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-019-0089-3#Fig2&#34;&gt;Figure 2&lt;/a&gt; in the paper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/sd-est_tot.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this plot, it is easier to see the changes in the migration rates estimation method. I was surprised that the changes in the estimates were occurring in all periods, not just the most recent period (2010-2015). To investigate I took a look at the changes in the WPP data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;which-countries-are-most-affected&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Which countries are most affected?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The largest revisions in the demographic accounting methods, especially those based on the closed accounting approach, can be detected by looking at the changes in net migration between WPP2017 and WPP2019. Below are the time series of net migration in nine countries. These countries were the location of the largest absolute differences (in any period) in net migration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/sd-wpp_big_changes.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a bit surprised by the scale of the changes. In some period’s revisions to net migration are greater than a million. I dug a little deeper into net migraiton in previous WPP revisions to find that similar revisions have occured before. Below are the revisions of absolute net migration between past WPP versions that exceed one million (back to WPP2000, the earliest WPP data I can get my hands on).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;htmlwidget-1&#34; style=&#34;width:100%;height:100%;&#34; class=&#34;widgetframe html-widget&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&#34;application/json&#34; data-for=&#34;htmlwidget-1&#34;&gt;{&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;url&#34;:&#34;/publication/bilateral-international-migration-flow-estimates_files/figure-html//widgets/widget_unnamed-chunk-2.html&#34;,&#34;options&#34;:{&#34;xdomain&#34;:&#34;*&#34;,&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;:false,&#34;lazyload&#34;:false}},&#34;evals&#34;:[],&#34;jsHooks&#34;:[]}&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;impact-on-validation-exercise&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Impact on validation exercise&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact on the validation exercise is minimal. Below is an update of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-019-0089-3#Fig4&#34;&gt;Figure 4&lt;/a&gt; in the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/sd-val_all.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The correlations change by few tenths of decimal. These small changes are due to the limited amount of reported migration flows statistics (at the global level) to carry out our validation exercise. In these 45 countries that we used (from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/en/development/desa/population/migration/data/empirical2/migrationflows.asp&#34;&gt;United Nations Population Division&lt;/a&gt; the revisions in the WPP data were relatively minor, hence only small changes in their estimates and the correlations with the reported data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate, Conflict and Forced Migration</title>
      <link>/publication/climate-conflict-and-forced-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/climate-conflict-and-forced-migration/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-zero trajectories for long-run net migration assumptions in global population projection models</title>
      <link>/publication/non-zero-ssp-net-migration-projections/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/non-zero-ssp-net-migration-projections/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-notes&#34;&gt;Further Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are some plots that I had to drop from the paper. Some reviewers liked them, reviewer three didn’t. The editor sided with the later, making a good point; they distracted from the main narrative of the paper. I have put them here as 1) I think they still might be of interest to some and 2) it took some effort to gather the net migration data from as many past versions of the World Population Prospects (WPP) as I could get my hands on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first plot shows estimates and future assumptions of net migration for all countries, as published by the United Nations DESA in past and current WPP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/abel-wpp-net1.png&#34; alt=&#34; &#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this plot I was trying to illustrate the differences between the volatile past estimates and the more regular future assumptions. It also shows how the assumption making has evolved to cover a longer period (up to 2100 from WPP2010 on-wards) and the use of the long run zero net migration trajectory, an assumption that seems to me to be overly complex given we know nothing about migration in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second plot slices the past data and future assumption a different way - looking at revisions in the WPP for each continent. These plots are similar to those that &lt;a href=&#34;http://webarchive.nationalarchives.gov.uk/20160108034027/http://www.ons.gov.uk/ons/rel/population-trends-rd/population-trends/no--128--summer-2007/fifty-years-of-united-kingdom-national-population-projections--how-accurate-have-they-been-.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Shaw (2007)&lt;/a&gt; used to illustrate assumption drift in the ONS national population projections.
&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/abel-wpp-net2.png&#34; alt=&#34; &#34; /&gt;
The assumptions in the past WPP also exhibit some drift, with assumptions for future net migration commonly immediately turning towards lower levels - where later observed estimates go on to show that a persistence assumption (without the turning point) would have been more accurate - see for example Africa or Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subnational gender balances in South Korea</title>
      <link>/publication/korea-gender-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/korea-gender-balance/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-notes&#34;&gt;Further Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An animated version of the plot in the paper I made when playing around with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thomasp85/gganimate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gganimate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/korea_srb.gif&#34; alt=&#34; &#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing internal migration flows patterns in South Korea</title>
      <link>/publication/korea-internal-migration-1970-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/korea-internal-migration-1970-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-notes&#34;&gt;Further Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please contact me if you would like the R code to produce the plot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimates of Global Bilateral Migration Flows by Gender between 1960 and 2015</title>
      <link>/publication/global-migration-estimates-by-gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/global-migration-estimates-by-gender/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-notes&#34;&gt;Further Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please contact me if cannot access the full paper and would like a copy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Internal Migration Flows 2010–2015 </title>
      <link>/publication/china-internal-migration-2010-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/china-internal-migration-2010-15/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-notes&#34;&gt;Further Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please contact me if you would like the R code to produce the plot (both the English and Chinese version).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an additional WeChat &lt;a href=&#34;http://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/gmv5iiJ5L-uNyI6vlGOhQA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on the paper (in Chinese) written by Qi Wei.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Vulnerability and Human Migration in Global Perspective</title>
      <link>/publication/global-climate-vulnerability-and-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/global-climate-vulnerability-and-migration/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
