<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chord diagram on Guy Abel</title>
    <link>/tags/chord-diagram/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chord diagram on Guy Abel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 &amp;middot; Selected posts also on &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-bloggers.com/&#34;&gt;R-bloggers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://rweekly.org/&#34;&gt;R Weekly&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/chord-diagram/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Global Migrant Stock Chord Diagrams</title>
      <link>/post/global-migrant-stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/global-migrant-stocks/</guid>
      <description>Over the last year or so I have been playing around with different ways of showing changing global bilateral migrant stocks, adapting the animation code I created for the plots for region to region flows in this estimation paper. I am putting them online here in case they are of interest to anyone else. Feel free to download the plots using right click over the animation and then Save Video as or from Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chord Diagram of Chinese Internal Migration Flows</title>
      <link>/post/chinese-migration-chord-diagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/chinese-migration-chord-diagram/</guid>
      <description>We have had a number of requests for the R code to replicate the plots in our paper on internal migration in China. The code below will produce a similar looking plot, but I have taken out some of the arguments that were very specific to our plot that will not replicate well for other data.
DataThe code is based on two data sets:
Bilateral flow data with three columns only (origin, destination and flow), see here for the file used belowRegion details used for plotting, see here for the file used belowNote, the names in the region data are the same as the ones used in the origin and destination data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional Migrant Stock Chord Diagrams</title>
      <link>/post/migrant-stock-chord-digrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/migrant-stock-chord-digrams/</guid>
      <description>During the last few months I have given some introductory talks on international migration in Asia and Europe. I had a couple of requests to share the animated chord diagrams that I created for others to use in their teaching materials. These are below, along with some extra plots for Africa, the Americas (Northern, Central and Southern America as well as the Caribbean) and Oceania. Feel free to download the plots using right click over the animation and then Save Video as or from Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated Directional Chord Diagrams</title>
      <link>/post/animated-directional-chord-diagrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/animated-directional-chord-diagrams/</guid>
      <description>BackgroundA little while ago my paper in International Migration Review on global migration flow estimates came out online. The paper includes a number of directional chord diagrams to visualize the estimates.
Recently I have been playing around tweenr and the magick packages for animated population pyramids. In this post I attempt to show how to use these packages to produce animated directional chord diagrams of global migration flow estimates</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
