<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Guy Abel</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Guy Abel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Guy Abel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining Traditional and Emerging Big Data Sources to Model Population Movement Patterns</title>
      <link>/project/combining-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/combining-big-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People move for many different reasons, related to their surrounding conditions at their origin and the potential gains at their chosen destination. In order to fully understand the causes and consequences of population movements, and how they evolve over time, researchers and policy makers require timely data. Traditionally movement data is obtained from censuses, administrative records or surveys, which tend to only give a brief picture of movement patterns prior to the data collection period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The development of new technology in recent decades has created new big data sets, based on the mobile phone call detail records and geolocated social media activates, with the potential to derive timely estimates of movements based on the analyst defined temporal and spatial scales.  At present, there has been little research to either compare or combine these big data sources. In this project we seeking to address this issue by firstly investigating movement patterns found in big data sources, and secondly, by applying a Bayesian statistical framework to combine them with traditional data sources. When combining data explicit adjustments can be made to correct for data problems such as undercount or biases, to provide synthetic databases of the true estimated movements, with measures of uncertainty&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
